In this lecture, we want to learn about Amazon Bedrock Architecture.
So, if you build any application on AWS,
you know there are two ways in which you can provision AWS services.
One way is within your AWS account, within your VPC,
you can provision services like EC2 RDS.
And then there is another approach where services like AWS Lambda function, API Gateway,
which are deployed in AWS service account within AWS VPC.
And Amazon Bedrock falls in the second category.
So, if you see here, Amazon Bedrock is deployed in the AWS Bedrock Service account.
So, that's the first thing to note.
Then we have the second AWS account where we have the model provider escrow account.
And this is AWS owned and operated.
So, this is where models from different service providers are hosted.
So, let's say we have another topic model and the artifacts of those base model
are going to be deployed in S3 bucket.
And then we have the runtime environment here, which is going to do the inferencing.
Now, let's go ahead and see how the requests are processed.
Earlier we discussed there are three ways in which you can make a request to the AWS Bedrock
Service. One is through the SDK. So, maybe you're using AWS Lambda and if you're using Python,
probably you'll use boot of three SDK.
Then through the browser, if you want to access it through the console,
then you can use the browser and then AWS CLI.
Now, let's say you have made an API request with the user input.
That request is going to go to this AWS Bedrock Service,
which will be within AWS Bedrock Service account.
And then it will be routed to this runtime inference.
And what this runtime inference does is it is used to redirect to the right model endpoint
based on the API request. So, within the API request, we discussed earlier here,
when we were looking at the API structure, we said we're going to provide the model ID,
like here we have an anthropic cloud. So, this runtime inference is going to interpret
the model ID and then it's going to route it to the right model product account where
inferencing for that particular model would be done.
So, now, if you're just accessing it from the console, then sometimes it can also store your prompt
history. But nothing would be stored in this AWS Bedrock Service, if the requests are coming from
AWS Lambda, which means the SDK or CLI. So, the reason why AWS has such an architecture
for Amazon Bedrock Service is because a lot of customers are worried that they're sending
their prompt and getting output from these models, which are posted in AWS. So,
there could be scenarios where the model provider might train his model on the customer data.
So, that's why this is hosted on and operated by AWS account so that model providers
do not train their models using customer data. So, last thing from the security perspective,
there are two ways in which you can send APA request to this Amazon Bedrock Service.
One is over the internet and the second one is through the VPC interface endpoints. So,
we know that when we send the request our VPC interface endpoints, they are routed privately
where the AWS AWS private network called us private link. Now, most enterprise customers prefer
routing the data over the VPC interface endpoints compared to the internet and the reason is
obviously there is less latency when you send the data or the private link and the second is
it is more secure. So, among the AWS account and if you can quickly show you the VPC interface
endpoints. So, let me just search for VPC and I have the VPC here. Now, if I just scroll down
and you can see here endpoints, I will click on the endpoints, just click on create endpoints
and if I just say select AWS service here and if I just search for Bedrock,
and you're showing all the endpoints that you can use to route the data or the private link through
the VPC interface endpoints. And you can see service name, we have calm dot Amazon AWS
US East, one Bedrock, and then you have one for agents, agent runtime, agent core, agent gateway,
and so on. Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see you in the next lecture. Thank you.